<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Signal &amp; Syntax: Practical AI Coding with Tom Archer</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Signal &amp; Syntax: Practical AI Coding with Tom Archer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should You Walk or Run in the Rain? The Puzzle That Sparked a Passion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/rain-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/rain-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure style=&#34;float: right; margin: 0 20px 10px 20px; width: 250px; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;./rain-paradox.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rain Paradox: Walk or Run?&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; style=&#34;display: block; margin: 0 auto;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption style=&#34;font-size: 0.9em; color: #555; margin-top: 5px;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;em&gt;To walk or to run. That is the question.&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early in my programming career, I came across a coding challenge that stuck with me for many years:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s raining, will you stay drier by walking or running through it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the skillset or tools to simulate the problem properly. It became one of the first exercises that nudged me toward a lifelong fascination with modeling the real world through code. The problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t about recursion or memory management. It was about &lt;strong&gt;getting wet&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;how fast you move through falling rain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Ice Shows to Algorithms: Cracking the Truck-Packing Puzzle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-d-packing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/three-d-packing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My very first programming job was with Holiday on Ice, a touring show that hauled entire arenas’ worth of scenery, props, and gear from city to city. Every week, the crew would break everything down and load it into trucks for the next destination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One day, the controller asked if I could write a program to figure out &lt;strong&gt;the most efficient way to pack those trucks&lt;/strong&gt;. I had already built their itinerary and box-office reporting systems, so I was comfortable with logic and basic math. But this was different. This was geometry, weight distribution, and optimization rolled into one giant puzzle — and at the time, I had no idea where to start.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
